Fried, John H. E.; Papers ger014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence and typescripts related to the UNESCO book project (published 1955, under the title: The Third Reich), ca. 1949-1952; 2; 2 cubic ft. 88 file folders
  - Wheeler-Bennett, John W., 1949-1954 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 87)
  - Wilson, Howard E., 1951 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence and typescripts related to ), Folder 88)
- United Nations Technical Assistance Administration (U.N.T.A.A), 1950-1954; 3; 8 folders
  This series contains correspondence and typescripts associated with the UNESCO book project, The Third Reich (1955). The correspondence is predominantly from the years, 1949-1952, although the inclusive dates of the entire series are 1938 to 1984. The typescripts are in English, French and German.
  - Personnel documents, 1950-1954 (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 89)
  - Appointment diary, 1952-1953 (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 90)
  - Memoranda, reports, 1951 July-1951 December (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 91)
  - Memoranda, reports, 1952 (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 92)
  - Memoranda, reports, 1953 (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 93)
  - Memoranda, reports, 1954 January-1954 April (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 94)
  - Agreements, 1948 April 01-1953 March 31 (Box 2 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 95)
  - Agreements, 1952-1954 (Box 3 (3-United Nations Technical Assistance ), Folder 1)
- Nepal, 1964-1966; 4; 61 file folders
  Nepal, 1964-1966. 61 file folders. Correspondence arranged alphabetically; memoranda arranged chronologically.
  This series contains primarily correspondence conducted by Fried during his years of service as United Nations Expert on International Law assigned to the Government of Nepal. Fried was located in Kathmandu, Nepal, 1964-1966. Included in this series are letters to relatives and especially letters to and from his first wife (Edrita), who became ill in Nepal and was forced to return to the U.S.
  Correspondence arranged alphabetically; memoranda arranged chronologically.
  - Contini, Paolo, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 2)
  - de Alwis, W. S., 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 3)
  - Dhital, Binod Prasad, 1964-1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 4)
  - Dikshit, Kumar Mani A., 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 5)
  - Fried, Edrita, 1964-1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 6)
  - Fried, John Jr., 1964-1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 7)
  - Fried, Stephen & Hetty, 1942; 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 8)
  - Gerner, Hellmut & Gerti, 1964-1968 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 9)
  - Gilead, A., 1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 10)
  - Grisogono, Guido, 1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 11)
  - Hardy, Michael, 1966-1968 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 12)
  - Kannan, P. K., 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 13)
  - Kesselstatt, John, 1964 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 14)
  - Khatri, Padma Bahadur, 1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 15)
  - Kiernik, Stanislaw, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 16)
  - Lande, Adolf, 1957; 1965; 1968 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 17)
  - Linnander, Gunnar, 1964 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 18)
  - Marcus, Ruth, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 19)
  - Marrett, Joseph E., 1964-1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 20)
  - Melford, John, 1966-1981 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 21)
  - Merghani, Hamzah, 1964 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 22)
  - Ortner, Franz V., 1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 23)
  - Pradhan, Hargovinda Singh, 1966-1990 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 24)
  - Pruscha, Carl, 1966; 1971 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 25)
  - Rana, T.P., 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 26)
  - Sauer, Doug, 1966-1967 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 27)
  - Schachter, Oscar, 1959-1970; 1989 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 28)
  - Schreiber, Marc, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 29)
  - Singh, Bhagbati Prasad, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 30)
  - Singh, K. B., 1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 31)
  - Singha, Jharendra Narayan, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 32)
  - Thapa, Bhekh B., 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 33)
  - Thapa, Surya Bahadur, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 34)
  - Tiwari, Padma Nath, 1965-1990 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 35)
  - Tsien, K. K., 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 36)
  - Upadhya, Devendra Raj, 1965-1975 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 37)
  - Upadhyay, Shailandra Kumar (Ambassador), 1973-1976 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 38)
  - Willam, Richard & Jane, 1966; 1972 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 40)
  - Correspondence re: second mission to Kathmandu, 1976 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 41)
  - Documents, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 42)
  - Personnel lists, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 43)
  - Memoranda, 1964 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 44)
  - Memoranda, 1965 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 45)
  - Memorandum: Fried, John H. E. "Comments on Draft Convention on Transit Trade of Land-locked States", 1965 May 13 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 46)
  - "Report on United Nations Plenipotentiary Conference, and Convention on Transit Trade of Land-locked States", 1965 July 08 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 47)
  - Fried, John H. E. "The New Convention on Transit Trade of Land-locked States, and the Development of Law under United Nations Auspices", 1965 August 25 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 48)
  - Fried, John H. E. "Convention on the Settlement of Investment Disputes between States and Nationals of Other States", 1965 September 19 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 49)
  - Fried, John H. E. "Optional Declaration by Nepal, Accepting the Jurisdiction of the World Court for Certain Disputes", 1965 October 31 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 50)
  - Fried, John H. E. "The 1965 Convention on Transit Trade of Landlocked States" (New Delhi), 1965 December 11 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 51)
  - Memoranda, 1966 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 52)
  - Fried, John H. E. "Final Report including some Comments and Suggestions, submitted to His Majesty's Government", 1966 July (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 53)
  - Fried, John H. E. "Law of the Sea. Comments on Part IV (Landlocked States) of the Single Negotiating Text", 1976 March 16 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous notes, typescripts, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 55)
  - Devendra, Raj Upadhya. "Transit Trade of Land-Locked States", 1974-1975 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 56)
  - Melford, J. B. "Land Code", 1965 September 13 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 57)
  - Ortner, Franz V. "Draft for a Building Code", Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 58)
  - Upadhyay, Shailandra Kumar. "Background Paper for the Establishment of a Common Heritage Fund in the Interest of Mankind as a Whole but Particularly in the Interest of Developing Nations", ca. 1978 (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 59)
  - Nepal-China Treaty, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 60)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials on Nepal, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 61)
  - Clippings on Nepal, Undated (Box 3 (4-Nepal), Folder 62)
- Somalia / French Somaliland, 1966-1970; 5; 48 file folders
  John Fried served as Legal Consultant to the Somalia delegation at the U.N. from 1966-1970. This series contains primarily reports composed by Fried on various issues dealing with Somalia / French Somaliland.
  - Drysdale, John G. S., 1968 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 1)
  - Farah, Abdulrahim Abby (Ambassador), 1966-1969; 1977 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 2)
  - Papanek, Jan (International League for the Rights of Man), 1967 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 3)
  - Thant, U, 1965-1968 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 4)
  - U.S. Department of Justice, 1966-1970 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 6)
  - Reports (primarily authored by John H.E. Fried) to Somali Ambassador Farah, 5.7 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 7-43)
    - Statement on French Somaliland, 1966 June (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 7)
    - Draft for Statement to the Committee of 24, regarding French Somaliland, 1966 October 05 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 8)
    - Historical claim by Ethiopia upon French Somaliland, 1966 October 08 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 9)
    - Statement delivered by the Hon. Abdirazak Haji Hussein, Prime Minister of the Somali Republic ..., 1966 October 18 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 10)
    - Draft for speech on Draft Res. A/L. 493, 1966 November 11 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 11)
    - Reply to Ethiopian assertion that French Somaliland should be designated as "Djibuti", 1966 November 29 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 12)
    - Short reply to proposal to call French Somaliland "so-called" French Somaliland, 1966 December 01 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 13)
    - Request for correction in Secretariat Working Paper on French Somaliland, 1967 March 04 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 14)
    - Statement made by H. E. Abdulrahim Abby Farah before the special committee of 24 on the Question of French Somaliland, 1967 March 09 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 15)
    - Letter to Editor-in-chief of Le Monde Paris, 1967 March 13 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 16)
    - Question of re-opening the Somalia-French Somaliland Border, and of negotiating with the French Government, 1967 March 29-1967 March 30 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 17)
    - Letter to the Editor, N.Y.T., 1967 March 30 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 18)
    - Statement by H.E. Ambassador Abdulrahim A. Farah before the Committee of 24, after the Committee has heard the petitioners from French Somaliland, 1967 April 03 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 19)
    - Draft of letter to H.E. the President of Niger, 1967 April 10-1967 April 11 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 20)
    - Draft outline for a speech on S. W. Africa, 1967 April 24 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 21)
    - Memorandum on the Preparation of a Detailed Reply to Kenya's Yellow Book, "Kenya-Somalia Relations", 1967 April (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 22)
    - Draft for communication to the Security Council, regarding Expellees from Fr. Somaliland, 1967 May 30 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 23)
    - Questions of International Law connected with the Utilisation of the Waters of the Webi Shebelli and Juba Rivers, 1967 August 10 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 24)
    - Universal Postal Union: Notification of Change of Name of French Somaliland (Preliminary observations by Legal Adviser), 1967 August 12 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 25)
    - Statement on French Somaliland in Committee of 24, 1967 September 10 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 26)
    - Revised draft of speech by H. E. the Minister of State of the Somali Republic in the General Debate, 27 September 1967 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 27)
    - Possible Somalia Aims regarding the NFD (Lusuka Mediation), 1967 October 08 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 28)
    - Legal Implications of the U.N. Declaration on Territorial Asylum, 1967 November 25 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 29)
    - Draft of Speech on French Somaliland, 1967 November 26 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 30)
    - Statement on Agenda item 96 (diplomatic immunities) in Sixth Committee, 1967 December 04 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 31)
    - Statement by the Permanent Representative of Somalia to the United Nations before the Fourth Committee of the XXII Session of the General Assembly on the Question of French Somaliland, 1967 December 12 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 32)
    - Statement in Fourth Committee on independence of Popular Republic of Yemen, 1967 December 13 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 33)
    - Draft for Letter to His Excellency, the Prime Minister regarding French Somaliland, 1968 February 14 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 34)
    - Somalia's over-all position at the U.N. regarding French Somaliland, 1968 March (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 35)
    - Memorandum by H. E. Ambassador Farah, 1968 July 22 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 36)
    - Draft for first intervention of H. E. Ambassador Farah in Special Committee of 24, 1968 September 02 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 37)
    - Draft for Second intervention by H. E. Ambassador Farah in the Special Committee of 24 opposing use of "Afar-Issa" name for French Somaliland, 1968 September 04 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 38)
    - Name of French Somaliland, 1968 October 17 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 39)
    - East Africa-French Afar and Issa Territory, 1968 October 22 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 40)
    - Draft Speech by H.E. Ambassador Abdulrahim A. Farah in Special Committee of 24, 1968 October 25 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 41)
    - Draft of Letter by H.E. Ambassador Abdulrahim A. Farah to the Chairman of the Special Committee of 24, 1968 October 28 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 42)
    - The services of the Legal Advisor ..., 1969 February 18 (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous notes, texts, Undated (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 44)
  - United Nations General Assembly publications re: Somalia, Undated (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 45)
  - Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, Undated (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 46)
  - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous materials, Undated (Box 4 (5-Somalia / French Somaliland), Folder 48)
- Vietnam and International Law and the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy, 1965-1990; 6; 76 file folders
  This series is divided into two sections. The first section contains typescripts and correspondence concerning Fried's collaborative work with Richard A. Falk entitled Vietnam and International Law. An Analysis of the Legality of the U.S. Military Involvement, published in 1967. The second section deals with Fried's activities with the with the Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam (1965-1975) and later with the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy (1981-1990). The series contains correspondence, as well as agenda, minutes of meetings and public statements.
  Arranged chronologically; correspondence arranged alphabetically.
  - Vietnam and International Law, 1966 July 04 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 49)
    Typescript, early version.
  - "Was the Introduction of U.S. military personnel and equipment into South Vietnam justified?", Undated; Typescript (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 50)
  - Vietnam and International Law. Reviews, Undated (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 51)
  - Reply to Prof. L. C. Green's substantive critique of Vietnam and International Law (AJIL), 1969 July (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 52)
  - Vietnam and International Law. Miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 53)
  - Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam, 1965-1971 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 54)
  - Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam - Nixon impeachment, 1972 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 55)
  - Fried trip to Hanoi, 1974 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 56)
  - Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam - Statement to Congress, 1975 January (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 57)
  - Lawyers Emergency Committee on the Illegality of the Neutron Bomb, 1978 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 58)
  - Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy (L.C.N.P.) - agenda, minutes, statements, 1981 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 59)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1982 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 60)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1983 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 61)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1984 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 62)
  - London Nuclear Warfare Tribunal, 1985 January 02-1985 January 06 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 63)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1985 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 64)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1986 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 65)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1987 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 66)
  - L.C.N.P. "Statement on the Illegality of Nuclear Warfare" (revised ed), 1987 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 67)
  - International Conference on Nuclear Weapons and International Law, New York, 1987 August 29-1987 August 31 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 68)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1988 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 69)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1989 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 70)
  - L.C.N.P. - agenda, minutes, statements, 1990 (Box 4 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 71)
  - The Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy. Newsletters, Undated (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 1)
  - The Lawyers' Committee on Nuclear Policy, Undated; clippings (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 2)
  - Fried, John H. E. "Report on My Trip to the USSR as a Member of the U.S. Peace Committee Delegation 22 Nov.-2 Dec. 1982", Undated (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re: book project on anti-nuclear quotations, 1983-1984 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 4)
  - Fried, John H. E. "Remarks on the Future of the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy", 1986 May 26 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 5)
  - Arbess, Daniel J., 1984-1986 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 6)
  - Arbess, Daniel J. / Simeon A. Sahaydachny, Undated; Reprint (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 7)
  - Ball, Lee H., 1982 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 8)
  - Banks, Russell, 1982 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 9)
  - Bertram-Nothnagel, Jutta, 1982-1987 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 10)
  - Bertram-Nothnagel, Jutta. "A Divided Doctrine for Marginal Occasions: The Illegality of Nuclear Weapons", 1981; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 11)
  - Birman, David, 1989-1990 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 12)
  - Birman, David. "Nuclear Free Zones and the Law", 1990 April; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 13)
  - Blishchenko, Igor P., 1979-1987 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 14)
  - Blishchenko, Igor P., Undated; Reprints (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 15)
  - Boehm, Robert L., 1969-1985 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 16)
  - Boudin, Leonard B., 1972-1979 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 17)
  - Boyle, Francis A., 1983-1987 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 18)
  - Boyle, Francis A., Undated; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 19)
  - Boyle, Francis A., Undated; Reprints, clippings (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 20)
  - Burn, Barbara B., 1983 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 21)
  - Cogan, Mark C., 1984 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 22)
  - Crown, Joseph, 1963-1989 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 23)
  - Crown, Joseph, Undated; Clippings (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 24)
  - D'Amato, Anthony, 1982-1986 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 25)
  - Dodson, Gwen, 1987 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 26)
  - Durland, Bill, 1982 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 27)
  - Falk, Richard A., 1966-1990 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 28)
  - Falk, Richard A. "Vietnam and International Law: The Past Recalled and the Future Challenged", 1990; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 29)
  - Falk, Richard A. "What's Wrong with Henry Kissinger's Foreign Policy", 1974 July (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 30)
  - Falk, Richard A. Publications, Undated; Clippings (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 31)
  - Goodman, Ernst, 1973-1986 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 32)
  - Henkin, Louis, 1967 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 33)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1967 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 34)
  - Meyrowitz, Elliott Lee, 1980-1986 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 35)
  - Meyrowitz, Elliott L. "Representation of the Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy on Peace Declaration to Soviet Union", 1982 November 20; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 36)
  - Miller, Alex, 1986-1988 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 37)
  - O'Hare, Eugene (O'Hare Books), 1966-1976 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 38)
  - Popper, Martin, 1966-1987 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 39)
  - Reich-Hilweg, Ines, 1983 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 40)
  - Rice, William, 1966-1967 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 41)
  - Sahaydachny, Simeon, 1986-1990 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 42)
  - Sahaydachny, Simeon. "Democracy Turned on its Head", 1984 December 07; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 43)
  - Sahaydachny, Simeon, Undated; Reprints, clippings (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 44)
  - Shriver, Donald W., Jr., 1982 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 45)
  - Standard, William L., 1965-1970 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 46)
  - Standard, William L. "Cold War - Endless War", ca. 1971; Typescript (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 47)
  - Steuer, Kathy, 1984 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 48)
  - Tunkin, Grigory I., 1978-1983 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 49)
  - Tunkin, Grigory I., Undated; Reprints, publications. (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 50)
  - Weiss, Peter, 1940-1990 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 51)
  - Weiss, Peter. Publications, Undated (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 52)
  - Zorn, Jean, 1984 (Box 5 (6-Vietnam and International Law and the ), Folder 53)
- General correspondence, 1938-1990; 7; 319 file folders
  The general correspondence files are arranged in four sub-categories: Fried's correspondence with former Nuremberg judges (17 file folders), general correspondence with individuals (201 file folders), correspondence with publishers (40 file folders), and correspondence with organizations (61 file folders).